Rodrigo Santana Gonçalves

Brazil / Brasília - DF rodrigosg2000@gmail.com https://rodrigoncalves.github.io

Software Developer with 8+ years of experience designing, developing and implementing applications and solutions using a range of technologies and programming languages both in Private and Public sectors. Seeking to secure a challenging position as a Blockchain Engineer. Possess BS in Software Engineering.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

RSK LABS, BUENOS AIRES, ARGENTINA

Blockchain Developer, January 2022 - Present

- Knowledge of cryptographic algorithms and techniques used in blockchain.
- Experience with smart contracts and building and deploying mobile/web dApps.
- Familiarity with frameworks like web3.js and ethers.js.
- Handle the entire life cycle of a blockchain application by creating marketplace architecture, making smart contracts and optimizing protocols. Development of mobile crypto wallet for end users.
- Experience with Solidity, React and React Native technologies.

BASIS INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY, BRASILIA, BRAZIL

Full Stack Developer, December 2020 - September 2024

- Allocation in internal demand projects of National Institute of Educational Studies and Research Anísio Teixeira (INEP), a government agency related to public education.
- Use Java and Angular technology to develop web applications for client server environments and add functionalities to existing applications.

GLOBALWEB CORP, BRASILIA, BRAZIL

Full Stack Developer, December 2018 – December 2020

- Consult with customers on project status and technical concerns about internal demands of Superior Court of Justice (STJ).
- Conduct user requirements analysis to design and program applications and deliver support for system enhancement.
- Play a pivotal role as a part of an Agile Scrum team accountable, developing new applications using Java Spring framework and Angular 10 frontend.

E-SEC DATA SECURITY TECHNOLOGY INC., BRASILIA, BRAZIL

Java and C++ Developer, September 2016 – December 2018

- Development and elaboration of software architecture for generation and verification of digital signatures. Manage digital certificate life cycle.
- Management of the digital certificate by developing mobile application with Android using Java language and drivers CSP/PKCS11 (C/C++).

NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY (ITI), BRASILIA, BRAZIL

Intern Developer, August 2015 – August 2016

 Development of plug-in in Adobe Reader for Verification of Digital Signatures ICP-Brasil (PKI) in PAdES standard in C/C++.

SKILLS

- Programming Languages/Frameworks: Java (Spring, Hibernate), Node.js, Angular 10, React, React Native. Docker
- Databases: MySQL, SQLite, PostgreSQL, SQLServer, DB2, MongoDB
- Cloud: AWS (EC2, RDS, S3, Route 53) and Firebase
- Advanced English

EDUCATION

Bachelor in Software Engineering, University of Brasília, July 2016

FREELANCE JOBS

- Web application development for a startup *Receita Digital*: Angular 8 + Node.js + AWS and Java iText Library for generation of signed PDF, 2020-2022.
- Mobile app development for Quero Aulas: Ionic + Firebase, 2019-2020.

of ICP-Brasi	il (PKI) Digital	to University of Brasília in development of plug-in in Adobe Reader for Gene Digital Signatures in the standard PadES, C/C++, 2018-2019.					